## lan Ames.

I help multidisciplinary teams deliver services in a user centred way.

## **Profile**

I have delivered projects to a range of Government organisations including the Cabinet Office, Dept for Culture Media and Sport, NHS Digital and TechUK.

At Land Registry I delivered their first user-centred Digital services meeting the <u>Service Standard</u>, as well as internal projects for 4000 distributed staff.

I have experience of a number of agile ways of working such as Scrum, Kanban, Cynefin, Lean and DevOps.

I have experience of leading co-located, distributed and fully remote teams. Clear communication and a shared understanding of goals is key, regardless of where your team is. I work hard to ensure teams are pulling in the same direction and are focused on the project outcomes.

I have spoken at meetups for Agile Southwest, Product Makers, Citizens Advice and Co-Op digital communities, and have presented at the FutureSync, <u>TechExeter</u>, and <u>Agile on the Beach</u> conferences. I have also helped facilitate the excellent <u>Agile in the Ether</u> and <u>Product in the (A)ether</u> meetups and conference.

## Career

#### **NHS Digital**

#### **Contract Product Manager, June 2022 to present**

Working with stakeholders and commissioners to understand strategy intent and goals. Understanding user needs to ensure our product meets them. Setting team priorities and ensuring value is delivered. Being the 'voice of the product' to the wider organisation.

#### Contract Delivery Manager, April 2021 - June 2022

Responsible for the delivery of designated products and services by one or more multi-disciplinary user-centred or software delivery teams.

#### **Delt Shared Services**

Innovation Specialist, September 2020 to April 2021.

Responsible for developing innovation at Delt, understanding our customers issues and challenges and exploring emerging technology and products to present and test solutions in a user centred and iterative way.

#### **Surevine**

Technical Team Lead, May 2019 to August 2020.

Responsible for developing a high performing remote team of software developers and testers, delivering customer projects and developing our working practices for efficient and effective agile software delivery.

### **HM Land Registry**

**Delivery Lead, 2014 - 2019.** 

I led a multidisciplinary team to develop the <u>Find Property Information service</u>. in a user-centric way using agile techniques based on the <u>Government Service Design Manual</u>. My team successfully passed the beta assessment of the <u>Government Digital Service</u> <u>Standard</u>. I advocated and acted as the voice of agile practice to the rest of the organisation.

New Services Manager, 2011 - 2014.

I acted as primary liaison between the development and operations departments to ensure a smooth transition of services to production. I was a Subject Matter Expert for cross functional requirements on projects. I developed a support process and change controls for services transitioning to production.

Senior Change Analyst, 2009 - 2011.

Configuration Analyst, 2007 - 2009.

Infrastructure Support Engineer, 2004 - 2007

#### **Vospers**

**Contract Systems Administrator, 2004** 

TWR/Menard Engineering

# **Projects**

## Patient Encounter History - 2021-22

Led the development of a product to enable clinicians from different parts of Urgent and Emergency Care to view information about patient encounters in other care settings in order to help diagnose complex cases, reassure patients and build rapport, and to identify worsening conditions. This was developed in a user centred way using Discovery to understand patient and clinical needs and Alpha to iteratively prototype and explore technical options.

## GPintheCloud, 2020 - 21

Led the development of a product to enable GP Locums to access clinical systems for multiple surgeries from one device securely. The service was developed based on user feedback and enabled Locums to support GP surgeries from anywhere in the country, crucial during the coronavirus pandemic, but a solution to the challenge of GP distribution across the country.

## Cyber Exchange, 2020

Project Lead for the delivery of Cyber-Exchange, a platform for UK Cyber Security businesses to connect, find funding opportunities and events . Sponsored by DCMS and Tech UK.

## **Future Vetting Service, 2019**

Project lead for the delivery of serverless future vetting website on AWS, with cross domain aspects on Docker Swarm, working closely with the NCSC and the Cabinet Office, leading a multi-disciplinary team of User Researchers , Designers , Developers , and Testers and supporting and coaching the teams Product Managers in Agile ways of working.

## Protect Alpha, 2018

A citizen focused service to allow citizens to easily protect their property interests. Keep their information on the register up to date, and to raise awareness of what Land Registry is and how we protect most people's largest asset, their home.

#### Find Property Information, 2016 - 17

A citizen focused service aimed at presenting basic land information for a number of user needs. Built on an entirely new infrastructure stack, including accounts, payment, audit, address API's. Migrated 24 million titles of land ownership data to a new database platform.

Developed our emerging agile practices and increased our deployment frequency from once a month to on-demand, completing 76 production deploys in 2017.

#### **Network transformation, 2015**

Led the design and procurement of a new multi-zoned and geographically dispersed network to support and protect over 70 land registry services, and the land register, part of the critical national infrastructure.

## Laptop Refresh, 2014

Delivered new laptops to 500 remote users, distributed throughout the country, along with a new remote working solution which simplified and expanded access to corporate services remotely. All within the time/cost/quality specs of the project.

#### Support Forum, 2013

Delivered a support forum/twitter feed, corresponding processes and training to provide users with the ability to search for solutions, report issues, ideas, or praise and allow Land Registry to gain valuable customer insight.

#### iPad and BYOD solution, 2013.

Rapid delivery of iPads to senior leaders and a corresponding system to access corporate information securely within 6 weeks, this enabled BYOD capabilities for HM Land Registry.

## **Education and Training**

Certified Scrum Master. Scrum Alliance 2015.

BSc (Hons) Marine Navigation. University of Plymouth, 1998 - 2001.

ITIL Practitioner in:

- Foundation
- Service Design
- Service Transition
- Service Desk and Incident Management
- Service Level Management

I have previously been SC cleared I have BPSS clearance

## **Contact Details**

plymames@gmail.com

07944876831

https://ames.world

LinkedIn

71 Somerset Place, Stoke, Plymouth, PL3 4BQ